A Guide to the Legislative Working Files and Tracking Documents, Secretary of the Commonwealth, 2010-2014 (bulk 2011-2013)
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Secretary of the Commonwealth, Legislative Working Files and Tracking Documents 2010-2014 (bulk 2011-2013)
The Library of Virginia
51155
.7 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Virginia. Secretary of the Commonwealth
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Office of the Governor, Patrick Henry Building, 1111 E. Broad Street, Richmond, Virginia, 23219, accession 51154 transferred on 23 January 2014.
Biographical/Historical Information
Robert F. McDonnell was elected 71st governor of the Commonwealth of Virginia in November 2009 and inaugurated on 16 January 2010. He served until 11 January 2014. Janet Vestal Kelly (f.k.a. Janet Polarek until 2012) served as the Secretary of the Commonwealth throughout McDonnell's tenure. She had previously served as the Chief Operations Officer during his gubernatorial campaign and as a staff member during his stint as Attorney General.
The Office of the Secretary of the Commonwealth has evolved from early colonial times when there existed a Secretary of the Colony. The Office became a gubernatorial appointment subsequent to a 1958 Act of the Assembly. The Secretary of the Commonwealth is under the jurisdiction of the Governor's Office. The Secretary is appointed by the Governor for a term of four years. Currently the Secretary of the Commonwealth is responsible for gubernatorial appointments, clemency and restoration of civil rights requests and extraditions. Other responsibilities include authenticating and certifying the records of the courts and of any state agency.
Scope and Content
The Legislative Files and Tracking Documents of the Secretary of the Commonwealth Janet V. Kelly are housed in 1 box. The collection is comprised of drafts and marked copies of proposed legislation, correspondence, memoranda, working papers, and other materials related to the consideration of legislation and its final disposition. Some of the notable legislative matters during Secretary Kelly's tenure including Virginia Government Restructure and Reform, Transportation Funding and Reform, the Virginia Freedom of Information Act, and the Commonwealth's Human Trafficking Action Committee.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically and alphabetically therein.
Related Material
The Governor Robert F. McDonnell Administration Web Archive Collection, 2010-2014 contains archived versions of websites for the Governor's Office, his initiative sites, and the sites of his cabinet secretaries, including Secretary of the Commonwealth Kelly. Also included are the related sites for the First Lady (Maureen McDonnell), as well as the Lt. Governor (Bill Bolling), and Attorney General (Ken Cuccinelli).
The Records of th Secretary of the Commonwealth's Governor's Fellows Program, 2010-2011 Collection
The Constituent Correspondence of Governor Robert F. McDonnell Collection
The Correspondence and Supporting Documentation of the Executive Office of Governor Robert F. McDonnell Collection
The Records of the Executive Mansion of Governor Robert F. McDonnell Collection
The Records of Governor Robert F. McDonnell's Secretary of Transportation Collection
The Records of Governor Robert F. McDonnell's Secretary of Administration Collection
The Records of Governor Robert F. McDonnell's Secretary of Administration Collection
Contents List
- Legislative Files and Tracking Documents, 2010-2014 (bulk 2011-2013).
  - Chippokes Plantation State Park 2011 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Human Trafficking (1 of 3) 2011 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Human Trafficking (2 of 3) 2011 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Human Trafficking (3 of 3) 2011 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Redistricting 2011 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Reform/Restructure (Government) 2011 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Restoration of Rights 2011 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Working Papers and General Legislative Material (1 of 3) 2011 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Working Papers and General Legislative Material (2 of 3) 2011 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Working Papers and General Legislative Material (3 of 3) 2011 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Adoption Services 2012 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Education 2012 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - General Assembly 2012 Session (1 of 2) 2012 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - General Assembly 2012 Session (2 of 2) 2012 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Reform/Restructure(Government) 2012 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Transportation Funding and Reform 2012 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Restoration of Rights 2012 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - SOC Lead Bills 2012-2013 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bills to Look Over 2013 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - SOC Comments 2013 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - UVA Board of Visitors 2013 (Box 2, Folder 9)